The boy with fair hair lowered himself down the last few feet of rock and began
to pick his way toward the lagoon.
Though he had taken off his school sweater and trailed it now from one
hand, his gray shirt stuck to him, and his hair was plastered to his forehead.
All around him the long scar smashed into the jungle was a bath of heat. He
was clambering heavily among the creepers and broken trunks when a bird,
a vision of red and yellow, flashed upwards with a witch-like cry, and this
cry was echoed by another. "Hi," it said. "Wait a minute." The undergrowth
at the side of the scar was shaken, and a multitude of raindrops fell,
pattering. "Wait a minute," the voice said. "I got caught up." The fair boy
stopped and jerked his stockings with an automatic gesture that made the jungle
seem for a moment like the home counties. The voice spoke again. "I
can't hardly move with all these creeper things." The owner of the voice came
backing out of the undergrowth so that twigs scratched on a greasy windbreaker.
The naked crooks of his knees were plump, caught and scratched by thorns.
He bent down, removed the thorns carefully, and turned around. He was
shorter than the fair boy and very fat.
He came forward, searching out safe lodgements for his feet, and then looked
up through thick spectacles. Where's the man with the megaphone? The fair boy
shook his head. This is an island. At least I think it's an island. That's a
reef out in the sea. Perhaps there aren't any grown-ups anywhere. The fat
boy looked startled. There was that pilot, but he wasn't in the passenger
cabin. He was up in front. The fair boy was peering at the reef through screwed up
eyes. "All them other kids," the fat boy went on. "Some of them must have got
out. They must have, mustn't they?" The fair boy began to pick his way as
casually as possible toward the water.
He tried to be off hand and not too obviously uninterested, but the fat boy
hurried after him. "Aren't there any grown-ups at all?" "I don't think so."
The fair boy said this solemnly, but then the delight of a realized ambition
overcame him. In the middle of the scar, he stood on his head and grinned at the
reversed fat boy. No grown-ups, the fat boy thought for a moment. That pilot,
the fair boy allowed his feet to come down and sat on the steamy earth. He
must have flown off after he dropped us.
He couldn't land here, not in a plane with wheels. We was attacked. He'll be
back all right. The fat boy shook his head. When we was coming down, I looked
through one of them windows. I saw the other part of the plane. There were
flames coming out of it. He looked up and down the scar. And this is what the
cabin done. The fair boy reached out and touched the jagged end of a trunk. For a
moment he looked interested. "What happened to it?" he asked. "Where's it
got to now?" That storm dragged it out to see. "It wasn't half dangerous with
all them tree trunks falling. There must have been some kids still in it." He
hesitated for a moment, then spoke again. "What's your name?" "Ralph." The
fat boy waited to be asked his name in turn, but this profer of acquaintance
was not made. The fair boy called Ralph smiled vaguely, stood up, and began to
make his way once more toward the lagoon. The fat boy hung steadily at his
shoulder. I expect there's a lot more of us scattered about. You haven't seen any
others, have you? Ralph shook his head and increased his speed. Then he tripped
over a branch and came down with a crash. The fat boy stood by him, breathing
hard. My auntie told me not to run, he explained on account of my asthma.
Asthma? That's right. Can't catch my breath. I was the only boy in our school
what had asthma, said the fat boy with a touch of pride. And I've been wearing
specks since I was three. He took off his glasses and held them out to Ralph,
blinking and smiling, and then started to wipe them against his grubby
windbreaker. An expression of pain and inward concentration altered the pale
contours of his face. He smeared the sweat from his cheeks and quickly
adjusted the spectacles on his nose.
"Them fruit," he glanced around the scar. "Them fruit," he said. "I expect."
He put on his glasses, waited away from Ralph, and crouched down among the
tangled foliage. I'll be out again in just a minute. Ralph disentangled
himself cautiously and stole away through the branches. In a few seconds,
the fat boy's grunts were behind him, and he was hurrying toward the screen
that still lay between him and the lagoon. He climbed over a broken trunk
and was out of the jungle. The shore was fledged with palm trees. These stood or
leaned or reclined against the light, and their green feathers were 100 feet
up in the air. The ground beneath them was a bank covered with coarse grass,
torn everywhere by the upheavalss of fallen trees, scattered with decaying
coconuts and palm saplings. Behind this was the darkness of the forest proper
and the open space of the scar. Ralph stood one hand against a gray trunk and
screwed up his eyes against the shimmering water. Out there, perhaps a
mile away, the white surf flal reef, and beyond that the open sea was dark blue.
Within the irregular ark of coral, the lagoon was still as a mountain lake,
blue of all shades and shadowy green and purple. The beach between the palm
terrace and the water was a thin stick, endless apparently. For to Ralph's left
the perspectives of palm and beach and water drew to a point at infinity, and
always almost visible was the heat. He jumped down from the terrace. The sand
was thick over his black shoes, and the heat hit him. He became conscious of the
weight of clothes, kicked his shoes off fiercely, and ripped off each stocking with its elastic
garter in a single movement. Then he leapt back on the terrace, pulled off
his shirt, and stood there among the skull-like coconuts with green shadows
from the palms in the forest sliding over his skin. He undid the snake clasp
of his belt, lugged off his shorts and pants, and stood there naked, looking at
the dazzling beach and the water. He was old enough, 12 years and a few months,
to have lost the prominent tummy of childhood, and not yet old enough for
adolescence to have made him awkward.
You could see now that he might make a boxer, as far as wit and heaviness of
shoulders went, but there was a mildness about his mouth and eyes that proclaimed
no devil. He patted the palm trunk softly, and forced at last to believe in
the reality of the island, laughed delightedly again, and stood on his
head. He turned neatly onto his feet, jumped down to the beach, knelt, and
swept a double arm full of sand into a pile against his chest. Then he sat back
and looked at the water with bright excited eyes. "Ralph." The fat boy
lowered himself over the terrace and sat down carefully, using the edge as a
seat. "I'm sorry I've been such a time.
Them fruit." He wiped his glasses and adjusted them on his button nose. The
frame had made a deep pink V on the bridge. He looked critically at Ralph's
golden body and then down at his own clothes. He laid a hand on the end of a
zipper that extended down his chest. My auntie. Then he opened the zipper with
decision and pulled the whole windbreaker over his head. There. Ralph
looked at him sidelong and said nothing.
I expect we'll want to know all their names, said the fat boy, and make a
list. We ought to have a meeting. Ralph did not take the hint, so the fat boy
was forced to continue. I don't care what they call me, he said
confidentially. So long as they don't call me what they used to call me at
school. Ralph was faintly interested.
What was that? The fat boy glanced over his shoulder, then leaned toward Ralph.
he whispered. "They used to call me Piggy."
Ralph shrieked with laughter. He jumped up. "Piggy, Piggy, Ralph, please." Piggy
clasped his hands in apprehension. "I said I didn't want Piggy, Piggy." Ralph
danced out into the hot air of the beach and then returned as a fighter plane
with wings swept back and machine gun Piggy. "Show!" He dived in the sand at
Piggy's feet and lay there laughing.
"Piggy!" Piggy grinned reluctantly, pleased to spite himself at even this
much recognition. So long as you don't tell the others. Ralph giggled into the
sand. The expression of pain and concentration returned to Piki's face.
Half a sec. He hastened back into the forest. Ralph stood up and trotted along
to the right. Here the beach was interrupted abruptly by the square motif
of the landscape. A great platform of pink granite thrust up uncompromisingly
through forest and terrace and sand and lagoon to make a raised jetty 4 feet
high. The top of this was covered with a thin layer of soil and coarse grass and
shaded with young palm trees. There was not enough soil for them to grow to any
height, and when they reached perhaps 20 ft, they fell and dried, forming a
criss-cross pattern of trunks, very convenient to sit on. The palms that
still stood made a green roof covered on the underside with a quivering tangle of
reflections from the lagoon. Ralph hauled himself onto this platform, noted
the coolness and shade, shut one eye, and decided that the shadows on his body
were really green. He picked his way to the seawward edge of the platform and
stood looking down into the water. It was clear to the bottom and bright with
the efflloresence of tropical weed and coral. A school of tiny glittering fish
flicked hither and thither. Ralph spoke to himself sounding the base strings of delight.
Wizo beyond the platform there was more enchantment. some act of God, a typhoon
perhaps, or the storm that had accompanied his own arrival, had banked
sand inside the lagoon, so that there was a long, deep pool in the
beach. With a high ledge of pink granite at the further end, Ralph had been
deceived before now by the specious appearance of depth in a beach pool, and
he approached this one, preparing to be disappointed. But the island ran true to
form, and the incredible pool, which clearly was only invaded by the sea at
high tide, was so deep at one end as to be dark green. Ralph inspected the whole
30 yards carefully, and then plunged in.
The water was warmer than his blood, and he might have been swimming in a huge
bath. Piggy appeared again, sat on the rocky ledge, and watched Ralph's green and white body
enviously. "You can't half swim, Piggy."
Piggy took off his so shoes and socks, ranged them carefully on the ledge, and
tested the water with one toe. It's hot.
What did you expect? I didn't expect nothing. My auntie sucks to your auntie.
Ralph did a surface dive and swam underwater with his eyes open. The sandy
edge of the pool loomed up like a hillside. He turned over, holding his
nose, and a golden light danced and shattered just over his face. Piggy was
looking determined and began to take off his shorts. Presently, he was paly and
fatly naked. He tiptoed down the sandy side of the pool and sat there up to his
neck in water, smiling proudly at Ralph.
Aren't you going to swim? Piggy shook his head. I can't swim. I wasn't
allowed. My asthma sucks to your Asmar.
Piggy bore this with a sort of humble patience. You can't half swim well.
Ralph paddled backwards down the slope, immersed his mouth and blew a jet of
water into the air. Then he lifted his chin and spoke. "I could swim when I was
five. Daddy taught me. He's a commander in the Navy. When he gets leave, he'll
come and rescue us. What's your father?"
Piggy flushed suddenly. "My dad's dead," he said quickly. "And my mom," he took
off his glasses and looked vainly for something with which to clean them. "I
used to live with my auntie." "She kept a candy store. I used
to get ever so many candies, as many as I liked. When will your dad rescue us?"
"Son as he can." Piggy rose dripping from the water and stood naked, cleaning
his glasses with a sock. The only sound that reached them now through the heat
of the morning was the long grinding roar of the breakers on the reef. How
does he know we're here? Ralph lulled in the water. Sleep enveloped him like the
swathing mirages that were wrestling with the brilliance of the lagoon. How
does he know we're here? Because, thought Ralph. Because the roar from the
reef became very distant. They'd tell him at the airport. Piggy shook his
head, put on his flashing glasses, and looked down at Ralph. Not them. Didn't
you hear what the pilot said about the atom bomb? They're all dead. Ralph
pulled himself out of the water, stood facing Piggy, and considered this
unusual problem. Piggy persisted. This an island, isn't it? I climbed a rock,
said Ralph slowly. And I think this is an island. They're all dead, said Piggy.
And this is an island. Nobody don't know we're here. Your dad don't know. Nobody
don't know. His lips quivered, and the spectacles were dimmed with mist. We may
stay here till we die. With that word, the heat seemed to increase till it
became a threatening weight, and the lagoon attacked them with a blinding
aulgence. "Get my clothes," muttered Ralph. "Along there." He trotted through
the sand, enduring the sun's enmity, crossed the platform, and found his
scattered clothes. To put on a gray shirt once more was strangely pleasing.
Then he climbed the edge of the platform and sat in the green shade on a
convenient trunk. Piggy hauled himself up, carrying most of his clothes under
his arms. Then he sat carefully on a fallen trunk near the little cliff that
fronted the lagoon, and the tangled reflections quivered over him. Presently
he spoke. We got to find the others. We got to do something. Ralph said nothing. Here was
a coral island protected from the sun.
Ignoring Piggy's ill-mened talk, he dreamed pleasantly. Piggy insisted. How
many of us are there? Ralph came forward and stood by Piggy. I don't know. Here
and there, little breezes crept over the polished waters beneath the haze of
heat. When these breezes reached the platform, the palm frrons would whisper
so that spots of blurred sunlight slid over their bodies or moved like bright
winged things in the shade. Piggy looked up at Ralph. All the shadows on Ralph's
face were reversed. Green above, bright below from the lagoon. A blur of
sunlight was crawling across his hair.
We got to do something. Ralph looked through him. Here at last was the
imagined but never fully realized place leaping into real life. Ralph's lips
parted in a delighted smile, and Piggy, taking the smile to himself as a mark of
recognition, laughed with pleasure. "If it really is an island, what's that?"
Ralph had stopped smiling and was pointing into the lagoon. Something
creamy lay among the ferny weeds. "A stone?" "No, a shell." Suddenly, Piggy
was a bubble with decorous excitement.
"It's right. It's a shell. I've seen one like that before. On someone's back
wall, a conch," he called it. He used to blow it and then his mom would come.
It's ever so valuable. Near to Ralph's elbow, a palm sapling leaned out over
the lagoon. Indeed, the weight was already pulling a lump from the poor
soil, and soon it would fall. He tore out the stem and began to poke about in
the water while the brilliant fish flicked away on this side and that.
Piggy leaned dangerously. Careful, you'll break it. Shut up. Ralph spoke
absently. The shell was interesting and pretty and a worthy play thing, but the
vivid phantoms of his daydream still interposed between him and Piggy, who in
this context was an irrelevance. The palm sapling, bending, pushed the shell across the weeds.
Ralph used one hand as a fulcrum and pressed down with the other till the
shell rose dripping and Piggy could make a grab. Now the shell was no longer a
thing seen but not to be touched. Ralph too became excited. Piggby babble piggy
babbled a conchk ever so expensive. I bet if you wanted to buy one, you'd have
to pay pounds and pounds and pounds. He had it on his garden wall and my auntie
Ralph took the shell from Piggy and a little water ran down his arm in color.
The shell was deep cream touched here and there with fading pink. Between the
point, worn away into a little hole and the pink lips of the mouth lay 18 in of
shell with a slight spiral twist and covered with a delicate embossed
pattern. Ralph shook sand out of the deep tube. Mood like a cow, he said. He
had some white stones, too, and a bird cage with a green parrot. He didn't blow
the white stone stones, of course, and he said. Piggy paused for breath and
stroked the glistening thing that lay in Ralph's hands. Ralph. Ralph looked up.
We can use this to call the others. Have a meeting. They'll come when they hear
us. He beamed at Ralph. That was what you meant, didn't you? That's why you
got the conchk out of the water. Ralph pushed back his fair. How did your
friend blow the conchk? He kind of spat, said Piggy. My auntie wouldn't let me
blow on a count of my asthma. He said you blew from down here. Piggy laid a
hand on his jutting abdomen. You try, Ralph. You'll call the others.
Doubtfully, Ralph laid the small end of the shell against his mouth and blew.
There came a rushing sound from its mouth, but nothing more. Ralph wiped the
salt water off his lips and tried again, but the shell remained silent. He kind
of spat. Ralph pursed his lips and squirted air into the shell, which
emitted a low farting noise. This amused both boys so much that Ralph went on
squirting for some minutes between bouts of laughter. He blew from down
here. Ralph grasped the idea and hit the shell with air from his diaphragm.
Immediately the thing sounded. A deep harsh note boomed under the palms,
spread through the intricacies of the forest, and echoed back from the pink
granite of the mountain. Clouds of birds rose from the treetops, and something
squealled and ran in the undergrowth.
Ralph took the shell away from his lips.
"Gosh!" His ordinary voice sounded like a whisper after the harsh note of the
conchk. He laid the conchk against his lips, took a deep breath, and blew once
more. The note boomed again, and then, at his firmer pressure, the note fluking
up an octave became a strident blare, more penetrating than before. Piggy was
shouting something. His face pleased.
his glasses flashing. The birds cried.
Small animals scuttered. Ralph's breath failed. The note dropped the octave.
Became a low wubber. Was a rush of air.
The conchk was silent, a gleaming tusk.
Ralph's face was dark with breathlessness, and the air of the island was full of bird clamor and
echoes ringing. I bet you can hear that for miles. Ralph found his breath and
blew a series of short blasts. Piggy exclaimed, "There's one." A child had
appeared among the palms about 100 yards along the beach. He was a boy of perhaps
six years, sturdy and fair. his clothes torn, his face covered with a sticky
mess of fruit. His trousers had been lowered for an obvious purpose and had
only been pulled back halfway. He jumped off the palm terrace into the sand, and
his trousers fell about his ankles. He stepped out of them and trotted to the
platform. Piggy helped him up.
Meanwhile, Ralph continued to blow till voices shouted in the forest. The small
boy squatted in front of Ralph, looking uprightly and vertically. As he received
the reassurance of something purposeful being done, he began to look satisfied,
and his only clean digit, a pink thumb, slid into his mouth. Piggy leaned down
to him. "What's your name," "Johnny?"
Piggy muttered the name to himself, and then shouted it to Ralph, who was not
interested because he was still blowing.
His face was dark with the violent pleasure of making the stupendous
noise, and his heart was making the stretched shirt shake. The shouting in
the forest was nearer. Signs of life were visible now on the beach. The sand,
trembling beneath the heat haze, concealed many figures in its miles of
length. Boys were making their way toward the platform through the hot,
dumb sand. Three small children, no older than Johnny, appeared from
startlingly close at hand, where they had been gorging fruit in the forest. A
dark little boy, not much younger than Piggy, parted a tangle of undergrowth,
walked onto the platform, and smiled cheerfully at everybody. More and more
of them came. Taking their cue from the innocent Johnny, they sat down on the
fallen palm trunks and waited. Ralph continued to blow short, penetrating
blasts. Piggy moved among the crowd, asking names and frowning to remember
them. The children gave him the same simple obedience that they had given to
the men with megaphones. Some were naked and carrying their clothes, others half-
naked or more or less dressed in school uniforms, gray, blue, fawn, jacketed or
jersey. There were badges, mottos, even stripes of color in stockings and
pullovers. Their heads clustered above the trunks in the green shade. heads
brown, fair, black, chestnut, sandy, mouse colored, heads muttering,
whispering, heads full of eyes that watched Ralph and speculated something
was being done. The children who came along the beach, singly in twos, leapt
into visibility when they crossed the line from heat haze to nearer sand. Here
the eye was first attracted to a black bat-like creature that danced on the
sand, and only later perceived the body above it. The bat was the child's
shadow, shrunk by the vertical sun to a patch between the huryanging feet. Even
while he blew, Ralph noticed the last pair of bodies that reached the platform
above a fluttering patch of black. The two boys, bullet-headed and with hairike
toe, flung themselves down and lay grinning and panting at Ralph like dogs.
They were twins, and the eye was shocked and incredulous as such cheery
duplication. They breathed together, they grinned together. They were chunky
and vital. They raised wet lips at Ralph, for they seemed provided with not
quite enough skin so that their profiles were blurred, and their mouths pulled
open. Piggy bent his flashing glasses to them and could be heard between the
blasts repeating their names. Sam, Eric, Sam, Eric. Then he got
muddled. The twins shook their heads and pointed at each other, and the crowd
laughed. At last, Ralph ceased to blow and sat there, the conchk trailing from
one hand, his head bowed on his knees.
As the echoes died away, so did the laughter, and there was silence. Within
the diamond haze of the beach, something dark was fumbling along. Ralph saw it
first and watched till the intentness of his gaze drew all eyes that way. Then
the creature stepped from mirage onto clear sand, and they saw that the
darkness was not all shadow, but mostly clothing. The creature was a party of
boys marching approximately in step in two parallel lines and dressed in
strangely eccentric clothing. Shorts, shirts, and different garments they
carried in their hands, but each boy wore a square black cap with a silver
badge on it. Their bodies, from throat to ankle, were hidden by black cloaks
which bore a long silver cross on the left breast, and each neck was finished
off with a hamone frill. The heat of the tropics, the descent, the search for
food, and now this sweaty march along the blazing beach had given them the
complexions of newly washed plums. The boy who controlled them was dressed in
the same way, though his cap badge was golden. When his party was about 10
yards from the platform, he shouted an order, and they halted, gasping,
sweating, swaying in the fierce light.
The boy himself came forward, vaulted onto the platform with his cloak flying,
and peered into what to him was almost complete darkness. Where is the man with
the trumpet? Ralph, sensing his sun blindness, answered him, "There's no man
with a trumpet, only me." The boy came close and peered down at Ralph, screwing
up his face as he did so. What he saw of the fair-haired boy with the creamy
shell on his knees did not seem to satisfy him. He turned quickly, his
black cloak circling. "Isn't there a ship, then?" Inside the floating cloak,
he was tall, thin, and bony, and his hair was red beneath the black cap. His
face was crumpled and freckled, and ugly without silliness. Out of this face
stared two light blue eyes, frustrated now, and turning or ready to turn to
anger. "Isn't there a man here?" Ralph spoke to his back. "No, we're having a meeting. Come
and join in." The group of cloaked boys began to scatter from close line, the
tall boys shouted at them, "quoir, stand still." Wearyily obedient, the choir
huddled into line and stood there swaying in the sun. Nonetheless, some
began to protest faintly, "But Meridu, please, Meridu, can't we?" Then one of
the boys flopped on his face in the sand, and the line broke up. They heaved
the fallen boy to the platform and let him lie. Meridu, his eyes staring, made
the best of a bad job. "All right then, sit down. Let him alone." "But Meridu,
he's always throwing a faint," said Meidu. He did in jib and Addis and it
mattens over the presenter. This last piece of shop brought sniggers from the
choir who perched like black birds on the criss-cross trunks and examined
Ralph with interest. Piggy asked no names. He was intimidated by this
uniformed superiority and the off-hand authority in Meidu's voice. He
shrank to the other side of Ralph and busied himself with his glasses. Meridu
turned to Ralph. Aren't there any grown-ups? No. Meridu sat down on a
trunk and looked around the circle. Then well have to look after ourselves.
secure on the other side of Ralph. Piggy spoke timidly. That's why Ralph made a
meeting so as we can decide what to do.
We've heard names. That's Johnny. Those two, they're twins, Sam and Eric. Which
is Eric? You? No, you're Sam. I'm Sam and I'm Eric. We'd better all have
names, said Ralph. So, I'm Ralph. We got most names, said Piggy. Got them just
now. Kids names, said Meridu. Why should I be Jack? I'm Meridu. Ralph turned to
him quickly. This was the voice of one who knew his own mind. then went on
piggy "That boy, I forget. You're talking too much," said Jack Meridu.
"Shut up, Fatty." Laughter arose. "He's not Fatty," cried Ralph.
"His real name's Piggy. Piggy! Piggy!
Oh, Piggy!" A storm of laughter arose, and even the tiniest child joined in.
For the moment the boys were a closed circuit of sympathy with Piggy outside,
he went very pink, bowed his head, and cleaned his glasses again. Finally, the
laughter died away, and the naming continued. There was Maurice, next in
size among the choir boys to Jack, but broad and grinning all the time. There
was a slight furt of boy whom no one knew, who kept to himself with an inner
intensity of avoidance and secrecy. He muttered that his name was Roger, and
was silent again. Bill, Robert, Harold, Henry, the choir boy who had fainted,
sat up against a palm trunk, smiled palidly at Ralph, and said that his name
was Simon. Jack spoke. "We've got to decide about being rescued." There was a
buzz. One of the small boys, Henry, said that he wanted to go home. "Shut up,"
said Ralph absently. He lifted the conchk. Seems to me we ought to have a
chief to decide things. A chief? A chief? I ought to be chief, said Jack
with simple arrogance. Because I'm chapter chister and head boy. I can sing
CP. Another buzz. Well then, said Jack.
I He hesitated. The dark boy, Roger, stirred at last and spoke up. Let's have
a vote. Yes, vote for chief. Let's vote.
This toy of voting was almost as pleasing as the conchk. Jack started to
protest, but the clamor changed from the general wish for a chief to an election
by a claim of Ralph himself. None of the boys could have found good reason for
this. What intelligence had been shown was traceable to Piggy, while the most
obvious leader was Jack. But there was a stillness about Ralph as he sat that
marked him out. There was his size, an attractive appearance, and most
obscurely, yet most powerfully, there was the conchk. The being that had blown that
had sat waiting for them on the platform with the delicate thing balanced on his
knees, was set apart. Him with the shell. Ralph. Ralph. Let him be chief
with the trumpet thing. Ralph raised a hand for silence. All right. Who wants
Jack for chief? With jury obedience, the choir raised their hands. Who wants me?
Every hand outside the choir except piggies was raised immediately. Then
piggy too raised his hand grudgingly into the air. Ralph counted, "I'm Chief,
then." The circle of boys broke into applause. Even the choir applauded, and
the freckles on Jack's face disappeared under a blush of mortification. He
started up, then changed his mind, and sat down again while the air rang. Ralph
looked at him, eager to offer something.
The choir belongs to you, of course.
They could be the army or hunters. They could be. The susion drained away from
Jack's face. Ralph waved again for silence. Jack's in charge of the choir.
They can be what do you want them to be?
Hunters. Jack and Ralph smiled at each other with shy liking. The rest began to
talk eagerly. Jack stood up. All right, choir. Take off your togs. As if
released from class, the choir boys stood up, chattered, piled their black
cloaks on the grass. Jack laid his on the trunk by Ralph. His gray shorts were
sticking to him with sweat. Ralph glanced at them admiringly, and when
Jack saw his glance, he explained. I tried to get over that hill to see if
there was water all around, but your shell called us. Ralph smiled and held
up the conchk for silence. Listen everybody, I've got to have time to
think things out. I can't decide what to do straight off. If this isn't an
island, we might be rescued straight away. So, we've got to decide if this is
an island. Everybody must stay around here and wait and not go away. Three of
us. If we take more, we'd get all mixed and lose each other. Three of us will go
on an expedition and find out. I'll go and Jack and and he looked around the
circle of eager faces. There was no lack of boys to choose from. And Simon the
boys around Simon giggled and he stood up laughing a little. Now that the pour
of his faint was over, he was a skinny, vivid little boy with a glance coming up
from under a hut of straight hair that hung down black and coarse. He nodded at
Ralph. I'll come and I Jack snatched from behind him a sizable sheath knife
and clouded it into a trunk. The buzz rose and died away. Piggy stirred. I'll
come. Ralph turned to him. You're no good on a job like this. All the same.
We don't want you, said Jack flatly.
Thre's enough. Piggy's glasses flashed.
I was with him when he found the conchk.
I was with him before anyone else was.
Jack and the others paid no attention.
There was a general dispersal. Ralph, Jack, and Simon jumped off the platform
and walked along the sand past the bathing pool. Piggy hung bumbling behind
them. "If Simon walks in the middle of us," said Ralph, "Then we could talk
over his head." The three of them fell into step. This meant that every now and
then Simon had to do a double shuffle to catch up with the others. Presently,
Ralph stopped and turned back to Piggy.
"Look." Jack and Simon pretended to notice nothing. They walked on. "You
can't come." Piggy's glasses were missed again, this time with humiliation. "You
told him after what I said." His face flushed, his mouth trembled. "After I
said I didn't want What on earth are you talking about? About being called Piggy?
I said I didn't care as long as they didn't call me
Piggy." And I said not to tell. And then you went and said straight out.
Stillness descended on them. Ralph, looking with more understanding at
Piggy, saw that he was hurt and crushed.
He hovered between the two courses of apology or further insult. "Better Piggy
than Fatty," he said at last, with the directness of genuine leadership. "And
anyway, I'm sorry if you feel like that.
Now go back, Piggy, and take names.
That's your job. So long." He turned and raced after the other two. Piggy stood,
and the rose of indignation faded slowly from his cheeks. He went back to the
platform. The three boys walked briskly on the sand. The tide was low, and there
was a strip of weedstrun beach that was almost as firm as a road. A kind of
glamour was spread over them and the scene, and they were conscious of the
glamour and made happy by it. They turned to each other laughing excitedly,
talking, not listening. The air was bright. Ralph, faced by the task of
translating all this into an explanation, stood on his head and fell
over. When they had done laughing, Simon stroked Ralph's arm shily, and they had
to laugh again. "Come on," said Jack presently. "We're explorers. Well
go to the end of the island," said Ralph, "and look around the corner. If
it is an island now toward the end of the afternoon, the mirages were settling
a little. They found the end of the island quite distinct and not magicked
out of shape or sense. There was a jumble of the usual squareness with one
great block sitting out in the lagoon.
Seabirds were nesting there. Like icing, said Ralph on a pink cake. We shan see
around this corner, said Jack, because there isn't one, only a slow curve. And
you can see the rocks get worse. Ralph shaded his eyes and followed the jagged
outline of the crags up toward the mountain. This part of the beach was
nearer the mountain than any other that they had seen. We'll try climbing the
mountain from here, he said. I should think this is the easiest way. There's
less of that jungly stuff and more pink rock. Come on. The three boys began to
scramble up. Some unknown force had wrenched and shattered these cubes so
that they lay a skew, often piled diminishingly on each other. The most usual feature of the
rock was a pink cliff surmounted by a skewed block, and that again surmounted,
and that again, till the pigness became a stack of balanced rock projecting
through the looped fantasy of the forest creepers. Where the pink cliffs rose out
of the ground, there were often narrow tracks winding upwards. They could edge
along them deep in the plant world, their faces to the rock. What made this
track? Jack paused, wiping the sweat from his face. Ralph stood by him,
breathless. Men. Jack shook his head.
Animals. Ralph peered into the darkness under the trees. The forest minutely
vibrated. Come on. The difficulty was not the steep ascent around the
shoulders of rock, but the occasional plunges through the undergrowth to get
to the next path. Here the roots and stems of creepers were in such tangles
that the boys had to thread through them like pliant needles. Their only guide,
apart from the brown ground and occasional flashes of light through the
foliage, was the tendency of slope.
Whether this hole, laced as it was with the cables of creepers, stood higher
than that. Somehow they moved up.
Immured in these tangles, at perhaps their most difficult moment, Ralph
turned with shining eyes to the others.
Wacko, wizard, smashing. The cause of their pleasure was not obvious. All
three were hot, dirty, and exhausted.
Ralph was badly scratched. The creepers were as thick as their thighs and left
little but tunnels for further penetration. Ralph shouted
experimentally, and they listened to the muted echoes. "This is real exploring,"
said Jack. "I bet nobody's been here before." "We ought to draw a map," said
Ralph, "Only we haven't done any paper."
"We can make scratches on bark," said Simon, "and rub black stuff in." Again
came the solemn communion of shining eyes in the gloom. "Wacko
wizard!" There was no place for standing on one's head. This time, Ralph
expressed the intensity of his emotion by pretending to knock Simon down, and
soon they were a happy heaving pile in the underdusk. When they had fallen
apart, Ralph spoke first. Got to get on.
The pink granite of the next cliff was further back from the creepers and trees
so that they could trot up the path.
This again led into more forest so that they had a glimpse of the spread sea.
With openness came the sun. It dried the sweat that had soaked their clothes in
the dark, damp heat. At last the way to the top looked like a scramble over pink
rock. With no more plunging through darkness, the boys chose their way
through defiles and over heaps of sharp stone. Look, look. High over this end of
the island, the shattered rocks lifted up their stacks and chimneys. This one,
against which Jack leaned, moved with a grading sound when they pushed. Come on.
But not come on to the top. The assault on the summit must wait while the three
boys accepted this challenge. The rock was as large as a small motor car.
Heave. Sway back and forth. Catch the rhythm. Heave. Increase the swing of the
pendulum. Increase. Increase. Come up and bear against that point of furthest
balance. Increase. Increase. Heave. The great rock loitered poised on one toe.
Decided not to return. Moved through the air. Fell. Struck. turned over, leapt,
droning through the air, and smashed a deep hole in the canopy of the forest.
Echoes and birds flew. White and pink dust floated. The forest, further down,
shook as with the passage of an enraged monster. And then the island was still
wacko, like a bomb.
Weeoo! Not for 5 minutes could they drag themselves away from this triumph, but
they left at last. The way to the top was easy after that. As they reached the
last stretch, Ralph stopped. Golly! They were on the lip of a circular
hollow in the side of the mountain. This was filled with a blue flower, a rock
plant of some sort, and the overflow hung down the vent and spilled lavishly
among the canopy of the forest. The air was thick with butterflies, lifting,
fluttering, settling. Beyond the hollow was the square top of the mountain, and
soon they were standing on it. They had guessed before that this was an island,
clambering among the pink rocks, with the sea on either side and the crystal
heights of air. They had known by some instinct that the sea lay on every side.
But there seemed something more fitting in leaving the last word till they stood
on the top and could see a circular horizon of water. Ralph turned to the
others. This belongs to us. It was roughly boat-shaped, humped near this
end, with behind them the jumbled descent to the shore. On either side
rocks, cliffs, treetops, and a steep slope. Forward there the length of the
boat, a tamer descent, treeclad with hints of pink, and then the jungly flat
of the island, dense green, but drawn at the end to a pink tail. There, where the
island petered out in water, was another island, a rock, almost detached,
standing like a fort, facing them across the green with one bold pink bastion.
The boys surveyed all this, then looked out to see. They were high up, and the
afternoon had advanced. The view was not robbed of sharpness by mirage. That's a
reef, a coral reef. I've seen pictures like that. The reef enclosed more than
one side of the island, lying perhaps a mile out, and parallel to what they now
thought of as their beach. The coral was scribbled in the sea as though a giant
had bent down to reproduce the shape of the island in a flowing chalk line, but
tired before he had finished. Inside was peacock water, rocks and weeds showing
as in an aquarium. Outside was the dark blue of the sea. The tide was running so
that long streaks of foam tailed away from the reef, and for a moment they
felt that the boat was moving steadily a stern. Jack pointed down. That's where
we landed. Beyond falls and cliffs there was a gash visible in the trees. There
were the splintered trunks and then the drag, leaving only a fringe of palm
between the scar and the sea. There, too, jutting into the lagoon, was the
platform, with insect-like figures moving near it. Ralph sketched a twining
line from the bald spot on which they stood, down a slope, a gully through
flowers, round and down to the rock where the scar started. That's the
quickest way back. Eyes shining, mouths open, triumphant, they savored the right
of domination. They were lifted up.
We're friends. There's no village smoke and no boats, said Ralph wisely. We'll
make sure later, but I think it's uninhabited. We'll get food, cried Jack.
Hunt, catch things until they fetch us.
Simon looked at them both, saying nothing but nodding till his black hair
flopped backwards and forwards. His face was glowing. Ralph looked down the other
way where there was no reef. Steeper, said Jack. Ralph made a cupping gesture.
That bit of forest down there. The mountain holds it up. Every point of the
mountain held up trees, flowers, and trees. Now the forest stirred, roared,
flailed. The nearer acres of rock flowers fluttered, and for a half a
minute the breeze blew cool on their faces. Ralph spread his arms. "All
ours!" They laughed and tumbled and shouted on the mountain. "I'm hungry."
When Simon mentioned his hunger, the others became aware of theirs. "Come
on," said Ralph. "We found out what we wanted to know." They scrambled down a
rock slope, dropped among flowers, and made their way under the trees. Here
they paused and examined the bushes around them curiously. Simon spoke
first. "Like candles! Candle bushes.
Candle buds. The bushes were dark evergreen and aromatic, and the many
buds were wax and green and folded up against the light. Jack slashed at one
with his knife, and the scent spilled over them. Candle buds? You couldn't
light them, said Ralph. They just look like candles. Green candles, said Jack
contemptuously. We can't eat them. Come on. They were in the beginnings of the
thick forest, plonking with weary feet on a track, when they heard the noises,
squeaking, and the hard strike of hoofs on a path. As they pushed forward, the
squeaking increased till it became a frenzy. They found a piglet caught in a
curtain of creepers, throwing itself at the elastic traces in all the madness of
extreme terror. Its voice was thin, needle sharp, and insistent. The three
boys rushed forward, and Jack drew his knife again with a flourish. He raised
his arm in the air. There came a pause, a hiatus. The pig continued to scream
and the creepers to jerk, and the blade continued to flash at the end of a bony
arm. The pause was only long enough for them to understand what an enormity the
downward stroke would be. Then the piglet tore loose from the creepers and
scured into the undergrowth. They were left looking at each other and the place
of terror. Jack's face was white under the freckles. He noticed that he still held
the knife aloft and brought his arm down, replacing the blade in the sheath.
Then they all three laughed ashamedly and began to climb back to the track. I
was choosing a place, said Jack. I was just waiting for a moment to decide
where to stab him. You should stick a pig, said Ralph fiercely. They always
talk about sticking a pig. You cut a pig's throat to let the blood out, said
Jack. Otherwise, you can't eat the meat.
Why didn't you? They knew very well why he hadn't. Because of the enormity of
the knife descending and cutting into living flesh. Because of the unbearable
blood. I was going to, said Jack. He was ahead of them, and they could not see
his face. I was choosing a place. Next time. He snatched his knife out of the
sheath and slammed it into a tree trunk.
Next time there would be no mercy. He looked round fiercely, daring them to
contradict. Then they broke out into the sunlight, and for a while they were busy
finding and devouring food as they moved down the scar toward the platform and the
meeting. Lord of the Flies.